TOPIC
    about_gpae_new_gpcommand

SHORT DESCRIPTION
    Describes how to use the New-GPCommand and New-GPFunction commands in the 
    GPAE SDK.

LONG DESCRIPTION
    The purpose of the commands in this module is to make it easier for you to
    develop your own PowerShell commands, scripts and functions that you can
    use to automate Group Policy settings. Most of the commands in this module
    are used to retrieve or set different parts of a GPO. Assembling these into
    a useful script can be a time consuming process. This module includes a few
    commands which serve as accelerators.
    
    With these commands you can build the framework for a PowerShell script or
    advanced function, complete with comment based help. The goal is to get as
    much of the "grunt" work out of script development so that you can focus on
    using the commands in this module to achieve your goals.
   
NEW-GPCOMMAND
    The New-GPCommand creates the framework for an advanced function based on
    user provided values.
    
    Parameters:
    Name <String>
    The name of the new function

    NewParameters <Hashtable>
    A hash table of new parameter values. The key should be the parameter name.
    The entry value should be the object type. You can also indicate if it should
    be an array by using [] with the object type.
    
    ShouldProcess [<SwitchParameter>]
    Set SupportsShouldProcess to True in the new function.
    
    Synopsis <String>
    Provide a brief synopsis of your command. 

    Description <String>
    Provide a description for your command.
    
    BeginCode <String>
    A block of code to insert in the Begin scriptblock.

    ProcessCode <String>
    A block of code to insert at the start of the Process scriptblock.

    EndCode <String>
    A block of code to insert at the start of the End scriptblock.

    UseISE [<SwitchParameter>]
    If you are running this command in the ISE, send the new function to
    the editor.
    
    New-GPCommand takes these parameters and constructs the code for an
    advanced function. The code is written to the pipeline. If you want to save
    the results, pipe it to Out-File. Or if you are running the command in the
    PowerShell ISE, the -UseISE parameter will open a new tab with your new
    command.
    
    For example, you might have a hashtable like this:
    
    $paramhash=@{Name="string[]";Test="switch";Path="string"}
    
    The key will be the new parameter name for your function and the value is
    the object type. You can also indicate if you want to accept an array as
    this example is doing for the Name key.

    From the prompt, you would run a command like this:
    
    New-GPCommand -name "Test-GPScript" -Newparameters $paramhash 
      -Synopsis "A test script" -description "This command sets a value"
      -ShouldProcess | out-file "c:\scripts\test-gpscript.ps1"   
      
    You would then open the file in your scripting editor and complete it. 
    
    Here's a more specific example of how you might use it with the SDK. First
    you make a connection to a container.
    
    $container = get-gpcontainer -path "User Configuration/Administrative Templates
    /System"-gpo $gpo

    You want to build a function to manage the "Prevent access to registry 
    editing tools" setting. To modify the settings you will need to use the 
    property names of the setting and you will need to know what type of object
    they are expecting. The Get-GPSettingPropertyType will provide that infor-
    mation and provide it as a hashtable.

    $sethash = $set | get-gpsettingpropertytype -AsHashTable
    
    This is what the hashtable looks like.
    
    Name                                   Value
    ----                                   -----
    Disable regedit from running silently? System.UInt64
    State                                  System.Int32

    Notice the property name can be long and have characters like a '?' that 
    can be problematic.
    
    Because almost always you will need a GPO object, we'll add a parameter to
    the hashtable. If you think you will always specify it as a GPO object you
    can do this:
    
    $sethash.Add("GPO","GPOSDK.GPObjectImpl")
    
    Otherwise set the type to a string and add code to get the GPO. Now you can
    build a new script.
    
    New-GPCommand -Name Set-RegTools -NewParameters $sethash -ShouldProcess
    
    This is what the end result looks like:
    
        Function Set-RegTools {
        <#
        .SYNOPSIS


        .DESCRIPTION


        .PARAMETER DisableRegeditFromRunningSilently 

        .PARAMETER State 

        .PARAMETER GPO 

        .NOTES
        These are the original parameter names. Some may have been modified.
        Depending on encoding any ? might really be a curly apostrophe.

        Disable regedit from running silently?
        State
        GPO

        #>

        [cmdletbinding(SupportsShouldProcess=$True)]

        Param (
        [System.UInt64]$DisableRegeditFromRunningSilently, 
        [System.Int32]$State, 
        [GPOSDK.GPObjectImpl]$GPO
        )

        Begin {
            Write-Verbose "Starting $($myinvocation.mycommand)"
            Import-Module SDM-GroupPolicy,GPAE
            
        }

        Process {
            
        }

        End {
            
            Write-Verbose "Ending $($myinvocation.mycommand)"
         }
         
        } #end Set-RegTools function

    You obviously need to edit the function to make it fully functional and
    you may want to adjust parameter names.
    
    Also note that the Begin script block is importing the GPAE module. It
    is assumed that any commands you build will rely on it.
    
NEW-GPFUNCTION
    The New-GPCommand tool is designed to be used broadly and could even be
    used to quickly generate non-GPO related functions. The GPAE module has
    another command called New-GPFunction that is specifically designed to take
    a Group Policy setting and create either a function to GET the settings or
    a function to SET it. This command uses New-GPCommand to generate the final
    function.
    
    To use, you need a setting object.
    
    PS C:\> $set | format-list

    Name    : Prevent access to registry editing tools
    GPsPath : \User Configuration\Administrative Templates\System
    Parent  : GPOSDK.GPContainerImpl
    Id      :
    
    Use this object as the value for the -Setting parameter to generate an
    advanced function.
    
    PS C:\> New-GPFunction $set
    
    Function Get-PreventAccessToRegistryEditingTools {
    <#
    .SYNOPSIS
    Getting GPO Settings from Prevent access to registry editing tools

    .DESCRIPTION
    This command will retrieve GPO settings for Prevent access to registry 
    editing tools under Administrative Templates.

    .PARAMETER GPO

    ...
    
    New-GPFunction creates most of the code you will need in the Process script
    block.
    
        Process {

        #if $GPO is a string get the GPO object
        if ($gpo -is [string]) {
            Write-Verbose "Retrieving GPO object for $gpo"
            $gpo=Get-GPAEGPO -Displayname $gpo
        }

        $setting=Get-GPSetting -Path "\User Configuration\Administrative Templates\System" -Name "Prevent a        ccess to registry editing tools" -gpo $gpo
        $settingobject=$setting | Get-GPSettingProperty

        #display formatted results
        $settingobject | Select-Object *,
         @{Name="Path";Expression={$setting.GPSPath}},
         @{Name="Setting";Expression={$setting.name}},
         @{Name="GPO";Expression={$setting.parent.gpo.name}}

        }
    
    You can test and edit as necessary. New-GPCommand will also create a SET
    function when you specify SET for the Action parameter.
    
    PS C:\> New-GPFunction $set -action set
    
    Much of the function is the same except that setting properties are turned
    into parameters.
    
        Param (
        [System.UInt64]$DisableRegeditFromRunningSilently,
        [System.Int32]$State,
        [object]$GPO
        )
    
    The Process script block also has code automatically generated to set the
    GPO setting.
        
        Process {

        #if $GPO is a string get the GPO object
        if ($gpo -is [string]) {
            Write-Verbose "Retrieving GPO object for $gpo"
            $gpo=Get-GPAEGPO -Displayname $gpo
        }

        $setting=Get-GPSetting -Path "\User Configuration\Administrative Templates\System" -Name "Prevent a        ccess to registry editing tools" -gpo $gpo
        $settingobject=$setting | Get-GPSettingProperty
        #THIS WILL NEED TO BE EDITED AND TESTED

        #Modify settings object with new values
        $settingobject.Disable regedit from running silently? = $DisableRegeditFromRunningSilently
        $settingobject.State = $State


        $setting | Set-GPSettingProperty -PropertyObject $settingobject
        }
        
    You will need to edit the function, especially watching for variable
    property names that have spaces, like:
    
        $settingobject.Disable regedit from running silently?

    You will need to modify it:
    
        $settingobject.'Disable regedit from running silently?'
        
    New-GPFunction only writes to the pipeline so you'll need to pipe the
    output to Out-File to save the results. The intention is that after you
    edit the Set-PreventAccessToRegistryEditingTools function, which could
    probably use a shorter name, you can run it like this:
    
        PS C:\> Set-RegEditTools -disable 1 -state 1 -gpo "MyTestGPO"
        
    This command should work fine with most GPO settings, although Preference
    settings may be a bit more complicated. The GPAE SDK includes a few 
    commands you can use to manage preferences as well as a model for your own
    scripting projects.
    
SEE ALSO
    about_gpae_basics
    about_gpae_sdk
    New-GPCommand
    New-GPFunction